我想每一种形式的激情都有
Well, passion I guess in every form
随着时间的推移而逐渐减弱的趋势。
has a tendency to damp down a little as time goes by.
无论是婚姻、
And whether it's passion in a marriage
友谊还是教学本身的激情，
or in a friendship or in teaching itself,
我们显然必须学会
we obviously have to learn to
以新的形式保持我们的激情，
to hold our passion in new forms
而这些激情也许
that aren't perhaps quite as on
并不像我们第一次发现
fire as they were when we first
这个人或这项工作时那样火热。
discovered this person or this work.
在我看来，激情变成了爱，
Passion becomes love it seems to me,
变成了我们学会
it becomes that steady flame of caring
在生活中保持的
about someone or something
对某人或某事的关心的稳定火焰。
that we learn to keep alive in our lives.
吹熄火焰的
What blows the flame out
部分原因是外部环境，
is partly external circumstances,
部分原因是管理者
it's partly administrators who
不理解培养从事工作的
don't understand the importance of
人的激情的重要性，
nurturing passion in the people doing the work,
部分原因是社会想把教师
it's partly a society which wants to use teachers
作为所有其他问题的替罪羊。
as a scapegoat for all its other problems.
都是因为这些外在的挫折。
It's all of these external discouragements.
但我也认为，在人类生活中，
But I also think that in human life,
有一段时间你不得不说，
there comes a time when you have to say
风在我周围吹得又冷又猛,
the winds are blowing cold and hard around me,
但我不必让内心的火焰熄灭。
but I don't have to let that inner flame go out.
事实上，我要对自己的生活负责，
In fact I'm responsible for my own life
我有责任让火焰继续燃烧。
and I'm responsible for keeping that flame alive.
而当我努力改变
And while I work to to change
社会的外部条件时，
the external conditions in the society,
我仍然需要在一个内在的旅程中，
I still need to be on an inner journey
我自己的身份完整和
where the question of my own integrity
我自己对生活的投资的问题
and my own investment in life
成为一个比这些其他人
becomes a much more important question
试图对我做什么的问题
than the question of what are these
更重要的问题。
other people trying to do to me.
所以你在成年后，
So you come to a point in adulthood I think
我认为你做出的最关键的决定是：
where the most critical decision you make is,
“我是要通过屈服于
"Will I conspire in my own diminishment
这些外部因素来阴谋削弱自己，
by succumbing to these external versus
还是要想办法进行内在的旅行，
or will I find ways to go on an inner journey
在我周围聚集一个支持我的社区，
and to gather around me a community of support
帮助保持这种火焰的活力，
that will help keep  that flame alive
这种身份完整以及承诺的火焰”。
that flame of integrity that flame of commitment".
我不知道成人生活中还有
I don't know of any more important question
什么问题比这更重要。
in adult life than that.
我认为我们在 "教学勇气 "
And I think that what we're trying to do
项目中要做的是，
in the courage to teach project is
帮助那些想为自己和
to help teachers who want to
自己的职业负责的教师找到接地气的、
take that responsibility for themselves and
负责任的、有力量的方法来做这些事情。
their vocation to find grounded responsible.
We must be willing to get rid of the life we planned so as to have the life that is waiting for us.
我们必须心甘情愿放弃我们所计划的生活，才能迎来正在等待我们的生活。